Aaron Boudreau

Detail-oriented and skilled front-end developer with a history in print and digital design. I have evolved into a skilled professional with a keen eye for aesthetics with a lens on accessibility. I bring a unique blend of skills and experience to any creative team; driving projects to excellence and ensuring they resonate with a diverse audience.

12 Silver Street Rochester, NH 03867

603 767 9169 bluepop4@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

Flylight Media, Portsmouth, NH — *Front-end Developer*

SEPTEMBER 2021 - PRESENT | FEBRUARY 2010 - OCTOBER 2011

Maintaining an internal front end build system that supports creating new website themes for the Umbraco CMS. Balancing component driven development with UI work exposing component properties for editors to work with. This includes writing custom integrations for third party services and working with custom CMS APIs for search functionality and/or complex frontend UI interactions.

Occasionally working with clients on print collateral such as point of sales sheets, small informational brochures or product branding.

MadPow, Portsmouth, NH - Sr. Creative Technologist

OCTOBER 2011 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Worked as part of a front-end development team providing a wide variety of front-end code from clickable prototypes for user testing to fully fleshed out UI kits. Provided education and guidance to client project teams to execute upon. Worked directly with UI/UX design team to navigate complex UI challenges while providing guidance on accessibility boundaries, responsive patterns and technical feasibility.

As a creative tech, I worked hand-in-hand with the design team to help establish and standardize vector graphics, color pallets, type scales and other UI building blocks to support a component-based design system for client projects. Balanced this with the technical challenges of working with client back-end teams to establish data points for defined components and front end assets needed to support them.

Russound, Newmarket, NH — *Graphic Designer*

APRIL 2005 - FEBRUARY 2010

Collaborated with product managers in creating support materials for in house audio products. Creative print materials included brochures, product briefs, mailers, sell sheets and company newsletters. Assisted in creating interactive demos for trade shows. Aided in the maintenance of the company website.

EDUCATION

Bristol Community College, Fall River, MA

Web certificate program, 2001

Marywood University, Scranton, PA

1994 - 1997

SKILLS

Front-end Development

Rapid Prototyping

Accessibility Testing

User Experience Design (UX)

User Interface Design (UI)

Interaction Design

Responsive Design

Graphic Design

Problem Solving

Adapability

Critical Thinking

TOOLS

Web Development

HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, Node, Gulp, webpack

Graphic/UI Design

Sketch, Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator

Print/Layout

Adobe Indesign